A Guide to the Russell Sage Foundation records, SG 3 FA413
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grants, 1965-2016; 1; 48.23 Cubic Feet 127 letter document boxes
  - Social Inequality
    - Buchmueller, Levy, and Wolfe - How Will the ACA Affect Health Disparities (83-14-13), 2014-2015 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cappellari - Parental Background and Students' Performance in Italy (83-09-08), 2009-2010 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Carnes - Why Do Millionaires Run our Country - Evidence from a National Survey of Party Leaders (83-13-09), 2013-2014 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Carnes - The Cash Ceiling - Why Only the Rich Hold Office and What You Can Do About It (83-15-21), 2015 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Cesarini - Wealth and Child Development (83-14-14), 2014-2015 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Charles - The Local Joneses - Household Consumption and Income Inequality in Large Metropolitan Areas (83-10-05), 2010-2013 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Clayton - A Symposium Examining the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and the Effects of the Shelby Decision on this Landmark Legislation (83-15-05), 2014-2015 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Dickert-Conlin - Inequality and Higher Education: Access, Persistence and Success (83-05-07), 2005-2007 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - DiPrete - SEC Sunshine and the Evolution of Executive Compensation Networks (83-12-06), 2012-2014 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Drennan - Linking Income Inequality to the Current Financial Crisis and Recession (83-10-06), 2009-2011 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Duncan - Social Inequality and Educational Disadvantage (83-08-06), 2014-2015 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Duncan - A Cross-National Study of SES Differences in and Adult Correlates of Age 7-10 Achievement, Attention and Behavioral Skills (83-09-10), 2009-2010 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Coley - Early Education and Care as a Mechanism to Ameliorate Socioeconomic Disparities in School Readiness Skills (AWARD DECLINED AND GRANT CANCELLED) (83-13-17), 2013 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - RSF - Educational Opportunity Task Force (83-07-07), 2007-2011 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Einstein - Divided Regions - Racial Inequality, Political Segregation, and the Splintering of Metropolitan America (83-13-10), 2013-2014 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Landais - Philanthropy and Welfare in the United States and European Countries - A Long Run Perspective (83-10-01), 2009-2011 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Landais - The Links Between Income Inequality, Charitable Giving, and Social Public Spending in the U.S. and Europe (83-08-08), 2008-2010 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Lazer and Ruths - Political Inequality in the Application of Money to Electoral Politics (83-14-03), 2014-2015 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Levy and Temin - Reinterpreting the Role of Institutions in the U.S. (83-07-01), 2005-2009 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Ludwig and King - Neighborhood and Social Inequality (83-09-02), 2009-2013 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Machin and Blandon - Mobility Relevant Attributes and Intergenerational Mobility - A Cross-Time and Cross-Country Analysis (83-09-17), 2009-2010 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Manza - Rich People's Movements - Individual Political Donors in an Age of Inequality (83-12-04), 2011-2013 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Manza and Brooks - Inequality and American Social Policy Attitudes (83-08-04), 2007-2013 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Mare - UCLA Project on Spatial Aspects of Inequality (83-02-02), 2002-2008 (Box 72, Folder 3, Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Social, Political, and Economic Inequality
    - Conley - Social Class - How Does it Work (83-06-01), 2005-2007 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Corcoran - The Politics of Inequality and Redistribution in U.S. Education Finance (83-07-04), 2006-2009 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Ellwood - The New Inequality - How Changes in Families, Higher Education, and Political Life are Affecting American Society (83-00-01), 2000-2006 (Box 29, Folder 5, Box 30, Folder 1-3, Box 32, Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Enns - Conference and edited volume on the Relationship Between Public Opinion and Inequality in the United States (83-08-07), 2007-2010 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Epstein - Income Inequality and Partisan Polarization - The View From Within Congress (83-07-14), 2007-2013 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Evans - Does Higher Family Income Produce Better Child Health - Evidence From the 1993 Expansion of the Earned Income Tax Credit (83-07-13), 2007-2013 (Box 31, Envelope 6)
    - Fernandez - Inequality, Education, and the Gender-Gap Reversal (83-09-03), 2008-2013 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Furstenberg - Families in the Middle - A Cross-National Study of Middle-Income Families in High-Income Economies (83-09-01), 2008-2013 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Genicot - Measuring Upward Economic Mobility (83-12-08), 2012-2013 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Geronimus - The Political Origins of Health Inequality - Political Parties and Infant Mortality (83-13-15), 2012-2014 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Gilens - Economic Inequality and Political Representation - Data Preparation and Archiving (83-12-05), 2012-2013 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Gilens - Inequality and Democratic Responsiveness (83-05-08), 2005-2009 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Gilens - Representational Inequality and Campaign Finance Regulation in the U.S. States (83-12-09), 2011-2013 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Grusky - Living in a High-Inequality Regime (83-11-02), 2011-2013 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Harris - Contemporary Racial Inequality in the United States (83-10-04), 2009-2012 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Heinrich - Pathways to Self-Sufficiency - Getting Ahead in an Era Beyond Welfare Reform (83-07-05), 2007-2009 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Hout - The New Inequalities: Social Dimensions of Economic Inequality (83-01-04), 2000 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - RSF - Integrative Activities for the Social Inequality Special Project (83-05-06), 2005-2010 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Jencks - Summer Institute Conference of the New Inequality Project (83-01-05), 2001-2006 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Jencks - Income Inequality and Children's Educational Outcomes (83-06-07), 2006-2008 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Jencks - To Replicate and Extend a Prior Analysis that Examined the Effects of Rising State-Level Income Inequality on the Educational Attainment of Teenagers (83-11-01), 2011-2015 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Jordan - Social and Economic Inequality - The Role of Law, Markets, and Social Structure, 83-06-05, 2005-2009 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Katznelson - APSA Taskforce on Religion and Democracy in the United States (97-07-04), 2006-2013 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Keene - Reverse Mortgages and Racial Inequalities in Wealth and Health (83-15-03), 2014-2016 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Keister - Religion and Inequality in America (83-12-03), 2011-2012 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Kenworthy - Material Well-Being Among the Poor: A Comparative Study (83-05-01), 2004-2008 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Konisky - Testing for Inequities in Environmental Enforcement - Government Performance and Environmental Justice (83-07-08), 2007-2009 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - McCall - Awareness of Inequality and Preferences for Redistribution - Have They Increased in the Era of Rising Inequality (83-03-01), 2002-2007 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - McCall - Preferences for Redistribution in the Market (83-13-07), 2013-2014 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Morenoff - Community Context, Prisoner Reentry, and Post-Prison Employment (83-08-01), 2007-2009 (Box 83, Folder 3-4)
    - Morgen - The Production of Tax Politics and Inequality - A Case Study of Tax-Related Ballot Initiative Campaigns in Oregon (83-14-12), 2014-2015 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Page - Affluent Americans and the Common Good (83-10-08), 2010-2013 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Payne - The Politics of Inequality in a Classless Society (83-13-06), 2013-2015 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Penner - The Consequences of Racial Fluidity for Inequality in the United States (83-09-05), 2009-2011 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Brooks and Phillips - The Politics of Inequality - Neighborhood-Level Allocations of Community Development Block Grant Money (83-07-03), 2006-2010 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Phillips - Who Listens to Whom - Assessing Inequalities in Representation (83-13-04), 2013-2015 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Plutzer - Economic Hardship, Family Life, and Voter Turnout in Developmental Perspective - Longitudinal Research on the High School Class of 1992 (83-04-03), 2003-2008 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Plutzer - Pathways from Poverty to Participation (83-13-12), 2013-2015 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Rahn - Supplemental Appropriation - Citizen Investors - The Democratization of the Stock Market and the Transformation of American Politics (83-07-11), 2010-2013 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Roemer - The Political Economy of Racism, Xenophobia and Distribution (83-03-03), 2002-2007 (Box 100, Folder 5-6)
    - Sastry - Dislocation and Return of New Orleans Residents After Hurricane Katrina (83-08-02), 2007-2009 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Scheve - The Conscription of Wealth - Mass Warfare and the Demand for Progressive Taxation (83-08-10), 2008-2010 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Schoeni - Health Effects of Non-Health Policy (83-06-02), 2005-2008 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Schur - The Distributional Impacts of Health-Related Government Tax and Program Expenditures - How Policy Contributes to Social Inequality (83-07-10), 2007-2009 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Skocpol - APSA Task Force on Inequality and American Democracy (83-03-04), 2003-2008 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Smeeding - Supplemental Appropriation - Intergenerational Mobility within and Across Nations (83-09-04), 2009-2011 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Smeeding - Is American Higher Education a Vehicle for Social Mobility (83-06-03), 2004-2009 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Smeeding - Economic Inequality, Public Goods Provision, and Social Outcomes - National and Cross-National Differences (83-01-02), 2000-2004 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - Soss - Making the Politics of Poverty and Inequality - How Public Policies Are Reshaping American Democracy (83-05-02), 2004-2007 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Soss and Bruch - Racial Relations in Understanding of the Politics of Inequality (83-13-13), 2013-2016 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - Owens - Economic Segregation of School Districts and the Income Achievement Gap (83-15-01), 2014-2015 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Turkheimer - Social Class and the Heritability of IQ (83-08-09), 2008-2009 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Lopez-Turley - Toward Equal Opportunity - Changes in the Effect of Socioeconomic Background on Educational Attainment (83-03-06), 2003-2006 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Wacquant - Conference on the Penal State (3-06-06), 2005-2007 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Wakefield - The Effects of Mass Incarceration on Inequality in the U.S. (83-10-03), 2009-2011 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Waldfogel - Inequality in Child Development and Public Policy in Australia, Canada, United Kingdom, and United States (83-12-07), 2012-2015 (Box 123, Folder 3-4)
    - Waldfogel - Inequality and the Black-White Test Score Gap (83-06-04), 2005-2008 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Waldfogel - Inequality in Early Childhood Education and Care (83-02-01), 2000-2003 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Walters - Award Cancelled - The Durable Divide of Race - Opportunity Hoarding and Policy Development in American Education from Brown to Vouchers (83-07-09), 2007 (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Western - The Effects of Economic Inequality on Civic Life and the Reciprocal Effects of Citizenship on Economic Distribution (3-01-06), 2001-2011 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Western - New Directions for Research on the Effects of Economic Inequality (83-13-08), 2013-2015 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Wolfe - Planning Meeting on the Relationship between Health, Biology and Socioeconomic Status (83-07-06), 2007-2008 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Wolfe and Evans - Toward Improving Our Understanding of the Tie between Socio-Economic Status and Health (83-08-03), 2007-2013 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Wolff - The Declining Importance of Inheritances or the Coming Inheritance Boom (83-08-11), 2008-2013 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Wright - Representing the Poor - Where, When and How Are the Interests of the Poor Represented in State Legislatures (83-07-02), 2006-2013 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Trust
    - Baron - Trust in Computerized Decision Aids (82-04-03), 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Barr and Patton - Trust, Trustworthiness and the Dynamics of Trustfulness - An Explanatory Research Proposal (82-01-08), 2002-2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Ben-Ner and Putterman - Determinants of Trusting and Trustworthiness (82-04-01), 2002-2007 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Bianco - Microfoundations of Political Trust (82-01-03), 2000-2004 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Boone and Buck - Communication of Trustworthiness - Affect Expression as the Mechanism for Building Trust and Cooperation (82-03-08), 2003-2008 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Brehm - Trust within Public Bureaucracies (82-00-02), 1999-2001 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Carruthers - Trust and Credit (82-02-03), 2001-2004 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Cook - Supplemental Appropriation - Capstone Volume for the Trust Initiative (82-07-01), 2004-2009 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Foddy - Group-Based Trust in Strangers - A Program of Cross-Societal Research (82-03-11), 2003-2008 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Hewstone - Sectarian Conflict and Cross-Community Trust in Northern Ireland (82-03-04), 2003-2008 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Hoffman - Trust Supporting Institutions and Economic Growth - Local Credit Markets in France, 1740-1899 (82-02-11), 2002-2005 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Lubell - Trust and Cooperation in Watershed Management (82-02-05), 2001-2007 (Box 70, Folder 1-2)
    - Oberholzer-Gee - Speed of New Ideas - The Role of Trust in the Diffusion of New Technologies (82-03-05), 2003-2004 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Posner - Ethnic Identity, Collective Action and Trust - An Experimental Approach (82-03-10), 2003-2009 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Sampson - Network and Community Dynamics of Working Trust (82-05-01), 2004-2007 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Shah - Media Effects on Social, Institutional, and Informational Trust (82-05-03), 2005-2007 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Slonim - Trust and Selective Discrimination (82-04-02), 2003-2007 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Sosis and Ruffle - Trust, Religion, and Signaling (82-05-02), 2005-2010 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Wuthnow - The Role of Trust in Social Service Delivery (82-01-10), 2004 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Visiting Scholars
    - Ermisch - Study Intergenerational Mobility, Focused on How Family Formation and Parental Behavior Affects Children's Subsequent Socioeconomic Mobility (83-09-11), undated (Box 33, Folder 9)